Guide to the Charles Hamm Recordings, 1857-1999 HAMM.2005
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Recordings on LP, 1
  - Popular, 1871-1999; IX.
    - ZZ Top: DeGuello, 1979 (Record HAMM POP 0365)
      This album includes I thank you (3:23) -- She loves my automobile (2:22) -- I'm bad, I'm nationwide (4:45) -- A fool for your stockings (4:15) -- Manic mechanic (2:36) -- Dust my broom (3:06) -- Lowdown in the street (2:49) -- Hi fi mama (2:22) -- Cheap sunglasses (4:46) -- Esther be the one (3:30).
    - ZZ Top: Fandango!, 1975 (Record HAMM POP 0366)
      This album includes Thunderbird / Gibbons; Hill; Beard (2 min., 49 sec.) -- Jail-house rock / Leiber; Stoller (1 min., 56 sec.) -- Backdoor medley: Backdoor love affair / Gibbons; Ham (1 min., 9 sec.); Mellow down easy / Dixon (3 min., 39 sec.); Backdoor love affair no. 2 / Gibbons (2 min., 4 sec.); Long distance boogie / Gibbons; Hill; Beard (2 min., 31 sec.) -- Nasty dogs and funky kings / Gibbons; Hill; Beard (2 min., 42 sec.) -- Blue jean blues / Gibbons; Hill; Beard (4 min., 42 sec.) -- Balinese / Gibbons; Hill; Beard (2 min., 37 sec.) -- Mexican blackbird / Gibbons; Hill; Beard (3 min., 6 sec.) -- Heard it on the X / Gibbons; Hill; Beard (2 min., 23 sec.) -- Tush / Gibbons; Hill; Beard (2 min., 14 sec.).
    - 25 Rock Revival Greats, 1972 (Record HAMM POP 0367)
      This album includes Rock around the clock (Bill Haley) -- Johnny B. Goode (Chuck Berry) -- Wake up little Susie (The Everly Brothers) -- Just because (Lloyd Price) -- The book of love (Monotones) -- Sh-Boom (The Crew Cuts) -- Black slacks (Sparkletones) -- Long tall Sally (Little Richard) -- Blueberry hill (Fats Domino) -- Born too late (Poni Tails) -- Rockin' Robin (Bobby Day) -- Bo Diddley (Bo Diddley) -- Chantilly Lace (Big Bopper) -- Surfin' U.S.A. (The Beach Boys) -- Wipe out (Surfaris) -- Sugar shack (Jimmy Gilmar) -- Great balls of fire (Jerry Lee Lewis) -- Where were you on our wedding day (Lloyd Price) -- Love potion number nine (The Clovers) -- The birds and the bees (Jewell Akens) -- Sheila (Tommy Roe) -- Glad all over (Dave Clark Five) -- Mission bell (Donnie Brooks) -- Soldier boy (The Shirelles) -- Oh, pretty woman (Roy Orbison).
  - Jazz, 1950-1988; VIII.
    This series consists of 49 albums. These albums represent a selection of American popular Jazz music over a thiry year period.
    - Albert Ayler: The Last Album, 1969, 1971 (Record HAMM JAZ 0001)
      This album includes Untitled duet (4:32) -- Again comes the rising of the sun (6:52) -- All love (8:59) -- Toiling (5:06) -- Desert blood (5:58) -- Birth of mirth (5:20) -- Water music (6:10).
    - Gato Barbieri: Under Fire, 1973 (Record HAMM JAZ 0002)
      This album includes El Paraná / G. Barbieri (9 min.) -- Yo le canto la luna / A. Yupanqui (4 min., 40 sec.) -- Antônico / I. Silva (3 min., 46 sec.) -- Maria Domingas / J. Benn (9 min., 35 sec.) -- El Sertão / G. Barbieri-S. Ricardo (8 min., 17 sec.).
    - Peter Bocage, 1961 (Record HAMM JAZ 0003)
      This album includes Mama's gone, goodbye.--I wish I could shimmy like my sister Kate.--Purple rose of Cairo.--Who's sorry now.--Bouncing around.--Hilarity rag.--Frogs legs rag.--The entertainer rag.--West Indies blues.--B-flat society blues.
    - Dave Brubeck's Greatest Hits, 1966 (Record HAMM JAZ 0004)
      This album includes Take five (P. Desmond) - I'm in a dancing mood (M. Sigler, A. Goodhart, A. Hoffman) - In your sweet way (D. Brubeck) - Camptown races (S. Foster) - The Duke (D. Brubeck) - It's a raggy waltz (D. Brubeck) - Bossa nova U.S.A. (D. Brubeck) - Trolley song (H. Martin, R. Blane) - Unsquare dance (D. Brubeck) - Blue Rondo a La turk (D. Brubeck) - Theme from Mr. Broadway (D. Brubeck).
    - The Dave Brubeck Quartet: Time Further Out (Miro Reflections), 1961 (Record HAMM JAZ 0005)
      This album includes It's a raggy waltz ((5:15) - Bluette (5:23) - Charles matthew Hallelujah (2:52) - Far more blue (4:380 - Far more drums (4:00) - Maori blues (3:550 - Unsquare dance (2:02) - Bru's boogie woogie (2:260 - Blue shadows in the street (6:33).
    - Paul Butterfield: Better Days, 1973 (Record HAMM JAZ 0006)
      This album includes New walkin blues.- Please send me something to love.- Broke my baby's heart.- Done a lot of wrong things.- Baby please don't go.- Buried alive in the blues.- Rule the road.- Nobody's fault but mine.- Highway.
    - The Butterfield Blues Band: East - West, 1966 (Record HAMM JAZ 0007)
      This album includes Walkin' blues -- Get out of my life, woman -- I got a mind to give up living -- All these blues -- Work song -- Mary, Mary -- Two trains running -- Never say no -- East-west.
    - The Paul Butterfield Blues Band: Incense, Herbs, Oil, 1965 (Record HAMM JAZ 0008)
      This album includes Born in Chicago(2:55) - Shake your money-maker (2:27) - Blues with a feeling (4:20) - Thank you Mr. Poobah (4:05) - I got my mojo working (3:30) - Mellow down easy (3:40) - Screamin' (4:30) - Our love is drifting (3:25) - Mystery train (2:45) - Last night (4:15) - Look over yonders wall (2:23).
    - Don Cherry: Relativity Suite, 1973 (Record HAMM JAZ 0009)
      This album includes Tantra.--Mali doussn'gouni.--Desireless.--The Queen of Tung-Ting Lake.--Trans-love airways.--Infinite gentleness.--March of the hobbits.
    - Bill Cole: First Cycle, 1980 (Record HAMM JAZ 0010)
      This album includes Sound Recordings, No linguistic Content.
    - Ornette coleman: Science Fiction, 1972 (Record HAMM JAZ 0011)
      This album includes What reason could I give.--Civilization Day.--Street woman.--Science fiction.--Rock the clock.--All my life.--Law years.--The jungle is a skyscraper.
    - Alice Coltrane with Strings: World Galaxy, 1972 (Record HAMM JAZ 0012)
      This album includes My Favorite Things - Galaxy Around Olodumare - Galaxy in Turiya - Galaxy in Satchidananda - Narration on love by Swami Satchindananda on A Love Supreme.
    - John Coltrane/Archie Shepp: New Thing at Newport, 1965 (Record HAMM JAZ 0013)
      This album includes Introduction (Father Norman O'Connor) -- One down, one up -- Rufus (Swung his face at last to the wind, then his neck snapped) -- Le matin des noire -- Scag -- Call me by my rightful name.
    - Ry Cooder: Jazz, 1978 (Record HAMM JAZ 0014)
      This album includes Big bad Bill is sweet William now -- Face to face that I shall meet him -- The pearls; Tia Juana -- The dream -- Happy meeting in glory -- In a mist -- Flashes -- Davenport blues -- Shine -- Nobody -- We shall be happy.
    - Chick Corea: Now He Sings, Now he Sobs, 1968, 1988 (Record HAMM JAZ 0015)
      This album includes Steps--what was -- Matrix -- Now he sings, now he sobs -- Now he beats the drum, now he stops -- The law of falling and catching up.
    - Jayne Cortez: Unsubmissive Blues, 1980 (Record HAMM JAZ 0016)
      This album includes side 1: You know.--For the brave young students in Soweto.--Ogun's friend.--side 2: Brooding.--In the morning.--The red pepper poet.
    - Larry Coryell: Barefoot Boy, 1971 (Record HAMM JAZ 0017)
      This album includes Gypsy queen -- The great escape -- Call to the higher consciousness.
    - Larry Coryell: Spaces, 1970 (Record HAMM JAZ 0018)
      This album includes Spaces (Infinite) (9:16) - Rene's Theme (4:06) - Gloria's step (4:290 - Wrong is Right (9:00) - Chris (9:31) - New Years Day in Los Angeles-1968 (0:20).
    - James Cotton Blues Band: Cotton in your Ears, 1968 (Record HAMM JAZ 0019)
      This album includes Back to St. Louis -- Motorized blues -- The mule -- With you on my mind -- I can't live without it -- (Please) Tell me partner -- Duke patrol -- Take me by the hand -- The coach's better days -- Take your hands off her.
    - Miles Davis in Cocnert, 1973 (Record HAMM JAZ 0020)
      This album includes Medley: Unknown B (cg out); Rated X (1); Honky tonk (1); Honky tonk (1) (incomplete); Right off (1); Black satin; The theme; Ife (1) (incomplete); Ife (cg out) (incomplete); Untitled original A; The theme.
    - Miles Davis: Live-Evil, 1971 (Record HAMM JAZ 0021)
      This album includes Sivad -- Little church -- Medley: Gemini; Double image -- What I say -- Nem um talvez -- Selim -- Funky tonk -- Inamorata and narration by Conrad Roberts.
    - Miles Davis: On the Corner, 1972 (Record HAMM JAZ 0022)
      This album includes On the corner/New York girl/Thinkin' one thing and doin' another/Vote for Miles.--Black satin.--One and one.--Helen Butte/Mr. Freedom X.
    - Don Ellis: Tears of Joy, 1971 (Record HAMM JAZ 0023)
      This album includes Tears of joy -- 5/4 getaway -- Bulgarian bulge -- Get it together -- Quiet longing -- Blues in elf -- Loss -- How's this for openers? -- Samba bajada -- Strawberry soup -- Euphoric acid.
    - Maynard Ferguson: Chameleon, 1974 (Record HAMM JAZ 0024)
      This album includes Chameleon (4:35) -- Gospel John (6:02) -- The way we were (3:25) -- Jet (3:55) -- La fiesta (8:04) -- I can't get started (3:42) -- Livin' for the city (4:55) -- Superbone meets the bad mad (5:08).
    - Maynard Ferguson: M.E. Horn, 1971 (Record HAMM JAZ 0025)
      This album includes Eli's comin -- Ballad to Max -- MacArthur Park -- Chala nata -- If I thought you'd ever change your mind -- L-dopa.
    - Pete Fountain/ Al Hirt: Bourbon Street, 1961 (Record HAMM JAZ 0026)
      This album includes Farewell blues -- St. James Infirmary -- March of the bob cats -- March through the streets of their city -- At the jazz band ball -- Blues on Bourbon Street -- Jazz me blues -- Lazy river.
    - Herbie Hancock: Head Hunters, 1973 (Record HAMM JAZ 0027)
      This album includes Chameleon /P. Jackson-H. Mason-B. Maupln-H. Hancock (15:41) - Watermelon Man /H. Hancock, Arr: Harvey Mason (6:29) - Sly /H. Hancock (10:18) - Vein Melter /H. Hancock (9:10).
    - Paul Horn: Inside II, 1972 (Record HAMM JAZ 0028)
      This album includes The mahabhutas (elements) / P. Horn -- Haida -- Bach chorales / J.S. Bach; arr. P. Horn -- Centaur (music composed for the film) / P. Horn -- Mass: Kyrie / G. Palestrina; arr. P. Horn.
    - Mississippi John Hurt: Today!, 1966 (Record HAMM JAZ 0029)
      This album includes Pay Day - I'm Satisfied - Gandy Man - Make Me a Pallet on the Floor - Talking Casey - Corrinna, Corrinna - Coffee Blues - Louis Collins - Hot Time in the Old Town Tonight - If You Don't want Me, Baby - spike Driver's Blues - Beulah Land.
    - Joseph Jarman: As if it were the seasons, 1968 (Record HAMM JAZ 0030)
      This album includes As if it were the seasons -- Song to make the sun come up -- Song for Christopher.
    - Keith Jarrett: Fort Yawuh, 1973 (Record HAMM JAZ 0031)
      This album includes (If the) misfits (wear it) -- Fort Yawuh -- De drums -- Still life, still life.
    - Jazz in Revolution: Big Bands in the 1940s, 1977 (Record HAMM JAZ 0032)
      This album includes Side 1. A-La-Bridges. - Dameron stomp. - The saint. - Elevation. -Five o'clock shadow. - Good jelly blues. - Mingus fingers. - Donna Lee. - Side 2. Perdido. - Zonky. - Tea for two. - I can't get up the nerve. - Mellow mood. - Royal roost. - The chase, Parts 1 & 2.
    - B.B. King: I Love You So, 1950, 1960 (Record HAMM JAZ 0033)
      This album includes I love you so - The woman I love - We can't make it - Treat me great - Time to say goodbye - Sweet thing - I've got papers on you baby - Tomorrow is another day - Come by here - The fool.
    - B.B. King: Indianola Mississippi Seeds, 1970 (Record HAMM JAZ 0034)
      This album includes Nobody loves me but my mother - You're still my woman - Ask me no questions - Untill I'm dead cold - King's special - Ain't gonna worry my life anymore - Chains and things - Go underground - Humminbird.
    - B.B. King: Live at the Regal, 1965 (Record HAMM JAZ 0035)
      This album includes Every day (I have the blues) -- Sweet little angel -- It's my own fault -- How blue can you get -- Please love me -- You upset me baby -- Worry, worry -- Woke up this mornin' -- You done lost your good thing -- Help the poor.
    - Pat Martino: The Visit!, 1972 (Record HAMM JAZ 0036)
      This album includes The visit -- What are you doing the rest of your life? -- Road song -- Footprints -- How insensitive -- Alone together.
    - Les McCann: Invitation to the Openness, 1972 (Record HAMM JAZ 0037)
      This album includes The lovers (26:11) -- Beaux J. Poo Boo (13:12) -- Poo Pye McGoochie (and his friends) (12:34).
    - John McLaughlin: Where Fortune Smiles, 1969, 1975 (Record HAMM JAZ 0038)
      This album includes Glancing backwards (8:54) -- Earth bound hearts (4:15) -- Where fortune smiles (4:01) -- New place, old place (10:24) -- Hope (7:19).
    - Pat Metheny Group: Still Life (Talking), 1987 (Record HAMM JAZ 0039)
      This album includes (It's just) talk (Special version) -- So may it secretly begin (Special version).
    - The One and Only Glenn Miller, 1968 (Record HAMM JAZ 0040)
      This album includes The man with the mandolin / Cavanaugh-Redmond-Weldon (2:51) -- (There'll be blue birds over) the white cliffs of Dover / Burton-Kent (2:55) -- Says who? Says you, says I! / Mercer-Arlen (2:43) -- Dearly beloved / Mercer-Kern (3:00) -- Three little fishies (itty bitty poo) / Dowell (2:56) -- Under blue Canadian skies / Lewis-Stock-Rose (3:05) -- I'm old fashioned / Mercer-Kern (2:45) -- Starlight and music / Hoffman-Kent-Hart (2:18) -- Goodbye, little darlin', goodbye / Marvin-Autry (2:52) -- Sleep song / Tobias-Reid (3:09).
    - Roscoe Mitchell: Sound, 1966 (Record HAMM JAZ 0041)
      This album includes Ornette.--The little suite.--Sound.
    - The Modern Jazz Quartet: Fontessa, 1956 (Record HAMM JAZ 0042)
      This album includes Versailles - Angel Eyes - Fontessa - Over the rainbow - Bluesology - Willow weepfor me - Woodyn you.
    - The Modern Jazz Quartet Plays Jazz Classics, 1965 (Record HAMM JAZ 0043)
      This album includes Concorde -- Django -- Delaunay's dilemma -- Milano --The queen's fancy -- La ronde -- La ronde suite --Vendome.
    - Archie Shepp: Live at Donaueschingen, 1968 (Record HAMM JAZ 0044)
      This album includes One for the trane (Parts 1 and 2).
    - Cecil Taylor: Unit Structures, 1970-1979 (Record HAMM JAZ 0045)
      This album includes Steps (10:15) -- Enter, evening (Soft line structure) (11:00) -- United structure/As of a now/Section (18:45) -- Tales (8 whisps) (7:10).
    - The Great Blues Men, 1972 (Record HAMM JAZ 0046)
      This album includes Set a date (Homesick James) (2:44) -- Dusty road (John Lee Hooker) (3:05) -- Corinna (Sleepy John Estes) (2:45) -- Nineteen years old (Muddy Waters) (4:55) -- San Francisco Bay blues (Jesse Fuller) (2:40) -- Blues in G (Mance Lipscomb) (3:33) -- If I had my way (Rev. Gary Davis) (3:05) -- Moanin' the blues (Mississippi John Hurt) (3:15) -- Stormy Monday blues (Junior Wells) (4:19) -- Dynaflow blues (Johnny Shines) (2:35) -- Empire State blues (Son House) (3:01) -- Mountain blues (Sonny Terry) (3:04) --It's all right, baby (Joe Turner, Pete Johnson) (2:30) -- Key to the highway (Brownie McGhee, Sonny Terry) (3:38) -- Burning fire (Otis Spann) (3:15) -- Cotton field blues (Lightning Hopkins) (5:36) -- Louise, Louise blues (Big Bill Broonzy) (2:55) --Tighten up on it (Johnny Young) (3:06) -- Ain't nobody's business (James Cotton) (3:23) -- How long, how long blues (Jimmy Rushing) (4:45) -- Cypress Grove blues (Skip James) (4:10) -- Please help (J.B. Hutto) (2:52) -- Fred's rambling blues (Fred McDowell) (2:05) -- Four day creep (Ida Cox) (3:25) -- On my way from Texas (Robert Pete Williams) (3:43) -- It's a mean old world (Otis Rush) (2:22).
    - McCoy Tyner: Song of the New World, 1973 (Record HAMM JAZ 0047)
      This album includes Afro Blue (9:58) -- Little Brother (10:13) -- The divine love (7:28) -- Some Day (6:49) -- Song of the New World (6:50).
    - Muddy Waters: Fathers and Sons, 1969 (Record HAMM JAZ 0048)
      This album includes All aboard -- Mean disposition -- Blow wind blow -- Can't lose what you ain't never had -- Walkin thru the park -- Forty days and forty nights -- Standin 'round crying -- I'm ready -- Twenty four hours -- Sugar sweet -- Long distance call -- Baby please don't go -- Honey bee -- The same thing -- Got my mojo working.
    - Junior Wells': Southside Blues Jam, 1971 (Record HAMM JAZ 0049)
      This album includes Stop breaking down -- I could have had religion -- I just want to make love to you -- Baby, please lend me your love -- You say you love me -- Blues for Mayor Daley -- I wish I knew what I know now -- Trouble don't last always (Buddy Guy, vocals).
  - Gospel, 1963-1981; VII.
    This series consists of four albums. These albums contain a selection of gospel music by various composers.
    - God's Trombones: A Festival of Worship, 1971-1972 (Record HAMM GOS 0001)
      This album includes 150th Psalm, Call to Worship - Amazing Grace, Prayer - Lord's Prayer - The Crucifixion - Lord's Prayer - When Israel was in Egypt Land - Let My People Go.
    - Bessie Griffin & The Gospel Pearls, 1963 (Record HAMM GOS 0002)
      This album includes Announcement and Are you sure -- Hold me -- Sweet home -- Didn't it rain -- Two wings -- Same train -- By the river -- I won't turn around -- Move up a little higher -- A gospel lullaby -- Wade in the water -- Caught up to meet Him.
    - The Young Hearts For Christ: Come Along With Me (Record HAMM GOS 0003)
      This album inludes Come along with me /Skillings / SESAC (1:57) - Did you ever hear God speaking to you /Salsbury / ASCAP (2:17) - Oh happy day /Hawkins / ASCAP (3:37) - Jesus made me higher /Omartian (3:10) - Illusive dream /Owen / ASCAP (2;24) - seek and Ye shall find (1:52) - A new world /Huff / BMI (2:58) - Amen /Arr. Carmichael / ASCAP (2:48) - If I live wwell praise the Lord /Hildebrand (1:57) - A quiet plqce /Carmichael / ASCAP (2:52) - Amazing grace -/P. D. (3:53).
    - Rev. Cleophus Robinson: The Lord Takes Care, 1981 (Record HAMM GOS 0004)
      This album includes The Lord takes care of everybody -- I've got to suffer for the Lord -- Help us Jesus -- Just over the hill -- Move over Satan -- I'm glad I made Him my choice -- Don't let the devil ride -- The day is passed and gone.
  - Foster, 1959, 1976; VI.
    This series consists of two albums. These albums showcase the music of early American composer and song writer Stephen C. Foster.
    - Songs by Stephen Foster, Vol. II, 1976 (Record HAMM FOS 0001)
      This album includes The voice of by gone days.--Better times are coming.--Linger in blissful repose.--There are plenty of fish in the sea.--My old Kentucky home, good night.--The soiree polka.--Larry's good bye.--Come where my love lies dreaming.--We are coming, Father Abraam, 300,000 more.--Come with thy sweet voice again.--Katy Bell.--Hard times come again no more.--Village bells polka.--The hour for thee and me.--Summer longings.
    - Stephen Foster Song Book: Robert Shaw, 1959 (Record HAMM FOS 0002)
      This album includes Only Song Book, No LP record included.
  - Folk, 1900-1988; V.
    Scope and Conent Notes
    This series contains 65 albums. The songs in these albums represent the style of Folk, whether they have no clear composer or simply fall into the style varies from album to album.
    - All-Star Hootenanny, 1964 (Record HAMM FLK 0001)
      This album includes This land is your land (The New Christy Minstrels) -- Down by the Glenside Kearney (Orriel Smith) -- John Henry (Pete Seeger) -- Worried man blues (Lester Flatt and Earl Scruggs with Mother Maybelle Carter) -- John Hardy (Leon Bibb) -- The whistling gypsy (The Clancy Brothers and Tommy Makem) -- Nine pound hammer (Johnny Cash) -- This train (The Brothers Four) -- Where have all the flowers gone (Pete Seeger) -- Brennan on the moor (The Clancy Brothers and Tommy Makem) -- Swing and turn jubilee (Carolyn Hester) -- Blowin' in the wind (Bob Dylan).
    - All Time Hootenanny Folk Favorites, 1960-1964 (Record HAMM FLK 0002)
      This album includes Goodnight Irene (The Weavers with Gordon Jenkins and His Orchestra); Lonesome Traveler (The Tarriers with Orchestra directed by Alan Greene); John Henry (Josh White); Sweet Betsy From Pike (Oscar Brand with The Tarriers); Careless Love (Bill Monroe and His Blue Grass Boys); Marching to Pretoria (Bob Gibson with orchestra directed by Jack Pleis); The Sinking of the Reuben James (The Gateway Singers); Michael (Wilburn Brothers); This Land is your Land (Tompall and the Glaser Brothers); Winkin Blinken and Nod (Ivy League Trio); Cindy (Sam Hinton); Greensleeves (Richard Dyer-Bennett).
    - America's Folk Heritage, 1960 (Record HAMM FLK 0003)
      This album includes disc 2. Stackoles; Cumberland Gap; Old time religion; Sourwood Mountain; Long John (Woody Guthrie); Green corn; Bury me high; Evil hearted me; Go way from my window (Josh White) --
      disc 3. Long time; Rainy day blues; Baby!; Long gone like a turkey thru the corn; Prison blues come down on me; Backwater blues; Gonna' pull a party (Lightnin' Hopkins); Down by the riverside; Blues for the lowlands; Right on that shore; Blowin' the fuses (Brownie and Sonny) --
      disc 4. Ridin' on down; Feelin' lowdown; Baby please don't go; St. Louis blues; In the evenin' (Big Bill Broonzy); Little wheel; I'm in the mood; Hobo blues; Crawling king snake; Blues before sunrise (John Lee Hooker) --
      disc 5. Hudson Street; Beach town; Holidays; About me; Summer; Tokyo; The rock (Rod McKuen); Dark as a dungeon; The tailor and the mouse; Banks of the Ohio; John Hardy; Suspiros del chanchomayo; Old maid's song; Lonesome Valley (Glenn Yarbrough) --
      disc 6. Road to Eliot; Ariran; Die Gendanken sind Frei; Bayeczo; Kisses sweeter than wine; In the evening when the sun goes down (Pete Seeger); In New Orleans; Goodnight Irene; Where did you sleep last night; How long (with Sonny Terry); John Hardy (Leadbelly).
    - Anthology of American Folk Music, Vol. 2, 1952 (Record HAMM FLK 0004)
      This album includes DANCES No. 1 & 2: Sail away Lady / Bunt Stephens; The wild Wagoner / J. W. Day; Wake Up Jacob / A. Hunt's Ramblers; La Danseuse / D. Lachney & Gaspard; Georgia Stomp / Andrew & Jim Baxter; Brilliancy Medley / Eck Robertson Family; Indian War whoop / F. Ming Pep-Steppers;Old Country Stomp / Henry Thomas; Old Dog Blue / Jim Jackson; Saut Crapaud / Columbus Fruge; Arcadian One Step / Joseph Falcon; Home Sweet Home / Breaux Freres; Newport Blues / Cincinnati Jug Band; Moonshiners Dance / F. Cloutier Orchestra; RELIGIOUS 1 & 2: Born Again; Oh Death / Rev. J. M. Gates; Rocky Road; Present Joys / Sacred Harp Singers; This Song of Love / Ga. singing Convention; Judgment / Sister M. Nelson; Better Things / Sanctified Singers; Laid My Burden Down / McIntorsh & Edwards; John the Baptist / Rev. Moses Mason; Dry Borns / Bascom Lunsford; John the Revelator / Blind willie Johnson; Little Moses / The Carter Family; Shine on Me / Phipps singers; 50 Miles of Elbow room / Rev. F. W. McGee; In the Battlefield / Rev. D. C. Rice.
    - David's Album, 1969 (Record HAMM FLK 0005)
      This album includes If I knew / Pauline Marden (2:46) -- Rock salt and nails / Bruce Phillips (3:47) -- Glad bluebird of happiness / Darryl Skrabak (2:53) -- Green, green grass of home / Curly Putnam (3:10) -- Will the circle be unbroken / trad. (4:16) -- The tramp on the street / Grady and Hazel Coll (3:26) -- Poor wayfaring stranger / trad. (4:36) -- Just a closer walk with Thee / trad. (4:00) -- Hickory wind / G. Parsons (3:35) -- My home's across the Blue Ridge Mountains / Thomas Ashley (4:11).
    - Joan Baez in Concert Part 1, 1964 (Record HAMM FLK 0006)
      This album includes Babe, I'm gonna leave you -- Geordie -- Copper kettle -- Kumbaya -- What they done to the rain -- Black is the color of my true love's hair -- Danger waters -- Gospel ship -- The house carpenter -- Pretty boy Floyd -- Lady Mary -- Ate amanha -- Matty Groves.
    - Recently, 1987 (Record HAMM FLK 0007)